Guide to the Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims and Henry Ward Beecher collection, 1819-1980 ARC.212
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 2: Plymouth Church, 1824-circa 1980; 2352; 9.6 Cubic Feet
  - Section 5b: Pastors - Newell Dwight Hillis, 2465
    - Book: Aftersermon Prayers., 1930; 2474 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Section 5c: Pastors - J. Stanley Durkee, 2475
    - Biographical information., circa 1925; 2476 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence., 1928; 2477 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Writings, sermons, lectures., 1940-1941; 2478 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Dedication of Durkee Memorial Library., 1938; 2479 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous- Ephemera, programs, and clippings., 1925-1926, 1937; 2481 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Book, Pull of the Invisible- signed; published volume of radio addresses., 1941; 2484 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Section 5d: Pastors - L. Wendell Fifield, 2490
    - Biographical and general information., 1941; 2491 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Writings, sermons., 1941, 1943-1955; 2492 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence., 1941-1943; 2493 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Radio Addresses., 1942-1943; 2494 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Invitations and replies to receptions for Fifield., 1941, 1951; 2495 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Installation., 1941-1942; 2496 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Resignation., 1954; 2497 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous- programs and clippings., circa 1941-circa 1955; 2498 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Section 6: History., 2458
    - "The Young Man"., 1894; 2627 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - 50th Anniversary Newsclip., 1897; 2628 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence regarding printing "Souvenir" of Plymouth Church., 1904; 2629 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - "Plymouth Church Statistics" from Plymouth Chimes Calendar., 1904; 2630 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Organization of Plymouth Church., 1912, 1924; 2631 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - "The Honor Roll"., 1918, undated; 2632 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Fire: Newsclipping., 1920; 2633 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Newsclippings., 1920-1924; 2634 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Paxton Hibben: Biography of HWB- reviews and correspondence., 1927; 2635 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence re: Plymouth Church Architecture., 1932; 2636 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Metropolitan Church Life- Announcement of service at Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims., 1934; 2637 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Portland vase: Clipping and letter re: gift of vase., 1934; 2638 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Department of the Interior press release re: Plymouth's aid to Metlakahtla Indians., 1937; 2639 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Advertising flyer for One Hundred Years of Plymouth Church., circa 1949; 2640 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - United Church Herald: article on Plymouth's designation as historical landmark., 1961; 2641 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Henry Ward Beecher: quotations., 1862; 2642 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Howard S. Bliss: Obituary and memorial., 1920; 2643 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - William E. Davenport: Correspondence and pamphlet., 1899-1929; 2644 (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Charles Dickens: Lecture at Plymouth., undated; 2647 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - Amorette E. Fraser: Luncheon: correspondence., 1934, 1937; 2648 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Reverend S.B. Halliday: Address given., 1894; 2649 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - Charles Halsey: memorial service., 1933; 2650 (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - John R. Howard: Correspondence and newsclips., 1856, 1897-1926; 2651 (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - John Tasker Howard: Correspondence and Newsclip., 1888; 2652 (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - Horatio C. King: Clippings and ephemera., 1876-1918; 2653 (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - Rossiter Wortington Raymond: Obit and biography., 1919-1935; 2654 (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - Dummy of "Plymouth Church: Its History, Membership, Chronology" edited by R.W. Raymond., 1904; 2655 (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - Captain Edward M. Smith: Memorial., 1920; 2656 (Box 27, Folder 32)
    - Augustus Storrs: Memorial., 1892; 2657 (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - Rose Ward: Newsclippings., 1927-1928; 2658 (Box 27, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous people of Plymouth: correspondence., 1901-1902; 2659 (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - Miscellaneous people of Plymouth: correspondence., 1927, 1970, 1972; 2660 (Box 27, Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous people of Plymouth., circa 1941; 2661 (Box 27, Folder 37)
    - Ephemera: Church under Hillis- Ribbons, receipts, clippings., circa 1899-circa 1929; 2662 (Box 27, Folder 38)
    - Ephemera: Church under Hillis- Programs, clippings., 1891-1938; 2663 (Box 27, Folder 39)
    - Ephemera: Miscellaneous., circa 1859-circa 1935; 2664 (Box 27, Folder 40)
  - Section 7: General, 2665
    - First Presbyterian Church., 1824, 1970; 2666 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - "The Illustrated Pilgrim Memorial"., 1863; 2667 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - "The Musical Critic and Trade Review"., 1881; 2668 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Church of the Pilgrims: "The Church of the Pilgrims After Forty Years of Pastoral Service" by Richard Storrs., 1886; 2669 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Church of the Pilgrims: Miscellaneous items., 1902, 1918; 2670 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Church Hymns: Publishing dummy., circa 1886; 2671 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous ephemera, including programs from other churches., 1901-1938; 2672 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Brooklyn Eagle Library, The New Onward Movement., 1904; 2673 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Notebook containing extracts from sermons and addresses by ministers, evangelists, religious teachers, and others., circa 1913-circa 1919; 2674 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous clippings re: Beecher., 1928; 2675 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Green-Wood Cemetery: materials pertaining to plot of Bond Family., 1934-1935; 2676 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - United Church of Christ, A.D. 1978: Photos of Beecher., 2677 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - History of Communion sets used at Plymouth Church., circa 1870, 1911; 2678 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Pilgrim origins (includes photos not transferred to Series 3) (includes photocopies and typescripts of 17th and 19th century material)., 1938-circa 1960s; 2679 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Plymouth, Massachusetts ephemera (includes postcards not transferred to Series 3), circa 1940; 2680 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Scroll presented to Beatrice Loenecke and Plymouth Church., 1969; 2681 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Section 8: Scrapbooks, 2682
    - Scrapbook of non-Beecher items - Newsclips and ephemera, principally New York City politics and amateur athletics., 1874-1887; 2683 (Box 61, Item 1)
    - Scrapbook presented to Plymouth Church by Marie A. Freckelton in memory of her parents, May 9, 1943 - Brooklyn, Plymouth Church, Beecher, England trip, and miscellaneous newsclippings and ephemera., 1863-1893; 2684 (Box 62, Item 1)
    - Scrapbook compiled by Shipman family - Brooklyn, Plymouth Church, Beecher, Bethel, Sunday School, poems, hymns, and miscellaneous newsclippings and ephemera., circa 1854-circa 1890s; 2685 (Box 63, Item 1)
    - Scrapbook complied by Frances Lee Pratt - Brooklyn, Plymouth Church, Sunday School, and Beecher newsclippings and ephemera., 1870s-1890s; 2686 (Box 64, Item 1)
    - Scrapbook leaves 1 of 2 - Brooklyn, Plymouth Church, and Beecher newsclippings and ephemera., circa 1868-circa 1908; 2687 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook leaves 2 of 2 - Brooklyn, Plymouth Church, and Beecher clippings and ephemera., circa 1868-circa 1908; 2688 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook leaves "Book 1" - Plymouth Church, Hillis, members, and Brooklyn newsclips (May 27-November 17)., 1901-1902; 2689 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Scrapbook by Horatio King - Morning service and other programs, with annotations and journal entries, with newsclips and ephemera concerning Plymouth Church, members, and Hillis., 1901-1907; 2690 (Box 65, Item 1)
    - Scrapbook re: both Beecher and Plymouth., circa 1887-circa 1907, 1916; 2691 (Box 66, Item 1)
- Series 3: Images, circa 1840s-circa 1966; 2692; 1.6 Cubic Feet
  The series is arranged generally by format, size of image, and subject matter.
  The bulk of the series includes images of Henry Ward Beecher in various formats, including engravings, cartes de visite, postcards, and cabinet cards, among others. Images of other individuals in the series include Rose Ward Hunt (i.e., "Pinky," or Sally Maria Diggs), Harriet Beecher Stowe, Lyman Beecher and other Beecher family members, Lyman Abbott and other Plymouth pastors, and others. There are also images of Plymouth Church and organizations associated with it.
  - Henry Ward Beecher: small images., circa 1840s-1880s; 2693 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - H.W. Beecher: medium images., circa 1856-circa 1887; 2694 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - H.W. Beecher: engravings., circa 1840s-1880s; 2695 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - H.W. Beecher: large engravings., circa 1880s; 2696 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - H.W. Beecher: large photographs., circa 1885; 2697 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - H.W. Beecher: large photographs., circa 1880s; 2698 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - H.W. Beecher and Eunice Beecher., circa 1884; 2699 (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - H.W. Beecher with others (in England; Harriet Beecher Stowe; others)., circa 1865-circa 1886; 2700 (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Beecher House and Summer House and Eunice Beecher., circa 1890; 2701 (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Beecher House and Eunice Beecher: large photographs., circa 1890; 2702 (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - H.W. Beecher and Eunice Beecher funerals., circa 1887-circa 1897; 2703 (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - H.W. Beecher sculptures., circa 1900, circa 1970; 2704 (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - H.W. Beecher: miscellaneous photographs., circa 1884-circa 1941; 2720 (Box 67, Folder 13)
  - Engravings for illustration of Beecher's trip to England., circa 1886; 2721 (Box 67, Folder 14)
  - Eunice Bullard Beecher., circa 1890s; 2722 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Beecher children (?)., undated; 2723 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Beecher family portraits., circa 1850s-circa 1890s; 2724 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Harriet Beecher Stowe., circa 1850s; 2725 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Lyman Beecher., circa 1850s; 2726 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Harriet E.B. Seaville., 1902; 2727 (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - "Pinky" (or Sally Maria Diggs), circa 1860; 2728 (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - "Pinky" (or Sally Maria Diggs) tintype, circa 1860; 4709 (Box Tintypes 1, Folder 1)
  - Fannie Virginia Casseopia Lawrence (former slave) (photo reproduction of 1863 photograph; see box 70)., 2729 (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Ellen Mitchell (former slave)., 1909; 2730 (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Lyman Abbott., circa 1888-circa 1899; 2731 (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - J.S. Durkee and Memorial Library., circa 1940; 2732 (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - L.W. Fifield., circa 1950s; 2733 (Box 68, Folder 12)
  - Newell Dwight Hillis., circa 1900; 2734 (Box 68, Folder 13)
  - Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims: interiors., circa 1900-circa 1958; 2735 (Box 68, Folder 14)
  - Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims: exteriors., circa 1950; 2736 (Box 68, Folder 15)
  - Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims: landmark plaque., 1962; 2737 (Box 68, Folder 16)
  - Plymouth Institute., circa 1920; 2738 (Box 68, Folder 17)
  - Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims: fire (November)., 1920; 2739 (Box 68, Folder 18)
  - Church Activities., 1917-circa 1966; 2740 (Box 68, Folder 19)
  - Beecher Missionary Society; Mrs. Arms of Mayflower., circa 1890s; 2741 (Box 68, Folder 20)
  - Tandem Club: rummage sale., 1952-circa 1960; 2742 (Box 68, Folder 21)
  - The Women's Guild., 1955-1956; 2743 (Box 68, Folder 22)
  - Unidentified/ Miscellaneous., circa 1880s-circa 1950s; 2744 (Box 68, Folder 23)
  - Printing plates: 18 total, including bill of sale and two images of "Pinky"., undated; 2745 (Box 69, Item 1-18)
  - 33 cartes de visite: 29 of Beecher; 1 of Eunice Beecher, 2 of other Beecher family members, and 1 of Fannie Virginia Casseopeia Lawrence., 1863-circa 1880s; 2746 (Box 70, Item 1-33)
  - 91 (approx.) cabinet cards: majority of Beecher, also includes Eunice Beecher, Lyman Abbott, Newell Dwight Hillis and various people related to Plymouth Church., circa 1860s-circa 1902; 2747 (Box 71, Item 1-)
  - 55 (approx.) postcards: majority of Plymouth Church/ Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims; also includes H.W. Beecher, the house where H.W. Beecher died, and N.D. Hillis., circa 1900-circa 1914; 2748 (Box 72, Item 1-)
  - Oversized items: Includes images of Harriet Beecher Stowe, Henry Ward Beecher, the Library at the Church of the Pilgrims, Newell Dwight Hillis, and Plymouth Church; satirical cartoons; the Freedom Certificate / Bill of Sale for Sally Maria Diggs ("Pinky"); newspapers on Tilton matter; printed sermons etc., circa 1853-circa 1900; 2749 (Box 73)
  - H.W. Beecher, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 24)